ALI HASSAN ELMAHDY

Mobile Application Developer

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

+971 58 581 1510

alyelmahdy56@gmail.com



About:

Strong professional with a bachelor's degree focused in Computer Science from the Faculty of Computer and Information Science / Egypt. Experience of several years in development with Android and Cross-platform (Flutter) applications and good knowledge of API services. Well-versed with different methodologies like Agile (Scrum), Retrofit & Reactive Programming as well. Worked with a team with excellent communication skills to accomplish the project with good quality.

Profiles:

Github https://github.com/alihassan20

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/alielmahdy/

Education:

2015 - 2019 Faculty Of Computer And Information System,

Mansoura University / Egypt, Computer Science (CS)

2018 - One Million Arab Coder

- Intensive Code Camp, Information Technology Institute (ITI) Track: Android Development

Professional experience:

2020-2022 INOUT (Flutter Developer)

2018-2020 Freelancer (Android/Flutter Developer)

Technical Skills:

- Flutter Framework
- Object Oriented Programming
- SOLID Principles.
- Data Structure and Algorithm.
- Python with Django Framework
- CMS (WordPress)
- Programming (Dart ,C# ,Java)
- Shared Preference, Get Storage
- State Management Solutions (Blocusing Cubit, Provider)
- Familiarity with REST APIs to connect applications to back-end services
- Versioning tool GitHub)
- Animation, Flutter Maps
- Firebase Auth, Firestore
 Database, Realtime Database

Projects/Sample:

AlQuran: Designed and built the application using flutter (Google

Play).

Al sahaba And Ta

baen:

Designed and built the application using flutter (Google

Play).

Circle: Designed and built the application using flutter (Google

Play).

Mansoura Co-Working Space:

.

Designed and built the application With Team using flutter

(Google Play).

Eat It: Displays many restaurants and menus, add it in a cart,

and makes an order (Video)

Akhbary: Sports and political All fields of news and searches for all

the news (Video).

E-Commerce App: Designed and built the application using flutter

Weather App: Real-time weather information based on your current

location using open weather API.

Online Sale: Displays and sells products online and searches for the

product you want.

Social App: Networking app like Telegram and Facebook app.

Text-Recognize: Convert the Text In Images To Text and use it.

Todo App: To recording daily tasks and set the time and date for

events and appointments.

Chat Application: Designed and built the application using flutter with using

Realtime Database.

Blood Donor One-To-One chat app in android application / Graduation

project at One Million Arab Coder.

Personal Skills:

Ability to work in a team

Leadership capabilities

Ability to work under pressure

Highly communication skills

Highly presentation skills

Quick Learner

Personal Information:

Date of Birth: 15 / 10 / 1996

Marital Status: Single
Nationality: Egyptian
Visa Status: Visit Visa

Languages: Arabic (Native)

English (V.Good)

References:

Available upon request